Mss.Ms.Coll.113
American Philosophical Society
- Series VI. Works by Others, 1.5 linear feet
  - International Scientific Community, 1971 March 30; 1.0 item; Porter, Richard W. (Richard William), 1913- (Box 26)
    Contains one (1) letter.
  - Black Holes in Galactic Centers, 1990 November; 1.0 item; Rees, Martin J., 1942- (Box 26)
  - The Particle and Field Environment of the Earth, 1968; 1.0 item; Roederer, Juan G., 1929- (Box 26)
  - X-Ray Astronomy, undated; 1.0 item; Rossi, Bruno Benedetto, 1905- (Box 26)
  - Distribution of Neutrino Fluxes from Pulsar Shells, 1981; 1.0 item; Shapiro, Maurice M. (Maurice Mandel), 1915-; Silberberg, Rein, 1932- (Box 26)
  - Confirmation of Dust Clusters in the Coma of Comet Halley, 1989; 1.0 item; Simpson, John A. (John Alexander), 1916-2000 (Box 26)
  - Evolution of Our Knowledge of the Heliosphere, 1989; 1.0 item; Simpson, John A. (John Alexander), 1916-2000 (Box 26)
  - Cosmic Dust Investigations II, 1989; 1.0 item; Simpson, John A. (John Alexander), 1916-2000 (Box 26)
  - Cosmic Dust Investigations I, 1989; 1.0 item; Simpson, John A. (John Alexander), 1916-2000 (Box 26)
  - Rocket Observations of Solar Chromospheric Fine Structure in the Light of Lyman Alpha, 1966; 1.0 item; Sloan, William A. (Box 26)
  - World Space Congress Presentation to the Committee on Space Research of the International Council of Scientific Unions, 1988 July; 1.0 item; Harford, James J.; Slotkin, Arthur L. (Box 26)
  - Columbus Day and the Frontier of Exploration, 1992; 1.0 item; Stone, Edward, 1936- (Box 26)
  - Changing GARP Dreams into Realities, undated; 1.0 item; Suomi, Verner (Box 26)
  - Six Years of Gamma-Ray Astronomy with Cos-B, 1981 November; 1.0 item; Taylor, B. G.; Wills, R. D. (Box 27)
  - Men of Space, Volume 7, Pages 51-77, 1961; 1.0 item; Thomas, Shirley (Box 27)
  - Two-Dimensional Position Sensing Si Detectors: Current and Charge Pulse Characteristics, 1988; 1.0 item; Tuzzolino, Anthony J., 1931- (Box 27)
  - The Coincidence Pulse Discriminator, unknown; 1.0 item (Box 27)
  - Fragment of Narrative, undated; 1.0 item (Box 27)
    This two-page undated narrative fragment, whose author is unknown, describes an experiment which observed solar x-rays covering an eleven-year solar cycle. The author comments that this experiment's results were published in Nature, and the results were put in question by James Warwick and Harold Zirin.
  - The Military Uses of Space, 1991 January 16; 1.0 item (Box 27)
  - On Discovering Atom Explosions, undated; 1.0 item (Box 27)
  - Present Status of Long Baseline Optical Interferometry, 1988 December 9; 1.0 item (Box 27)
  - Significance of New Tubes Originated By Herbert Friedman for Radiac Instruments, undated; 1.0 item (Box 27)
  - Untitled Manuscript, 1984 August 6; 1.0 item (Box 27)
    This untitled manuscript spans 120 pages. The only "title" it seems to have is a notation at the top: ICSU-IGBP - Tape 1, Side A, August 6, 1984. It seems to set forth a theory regarding climate change and tectonic plate movement.
  - Untitled Partial Manuscript, undated; 1.0 item (Box 27)
    This partial manuscript spans seven pages. At the bottom is superscript that states "Chapter 9 -- Sun and Earth.
  - Jupiter's Magnetosphere as Observed By Pioneer 10, 1974; 2.0 items; Randall, Roger F.; Van Allen, James A. (James Alfred), 1914-2006 (Box 27)
  - Oral History with Dr. Herbert Friedman, 1989 July 24; 1.0 item; Van Keuren, David K. (Box 27)
  - Before the Beginning, 1984 January-February; 1.0 item; Waldrop, M. Mitchell (Box 27)
  - The Moon and Sixpence of Science, undated; 1.0 item; Wasserburg, Gerald J. (Gerald Joseph), 1927- (Box 27)
  - The Fogging of Photographic Film By Radioactive Contaminants in Cardboard Packaging Materials, 1949 August 1; 1.0 item; Webb, J. H. (John Harold), 1942- (Box 27)
  - The Lesson of the Black Hole, 1981 February; 1.0 item; Wheeler, John Archibald, 1911-2008 (Box 27)
  - XLA: X-Ray Large Array, 1986 June 25; 1.0 item; Hertz, Paul Louis; Michelson, Peter F.; Wood, K. S. (Box 27)
  - Waiting for Joe-1: Decisions Leading to the Detection of Russia's First Atomic Bomb Test, 1988 May; 1.0 item; Ziegler, Charles A. (Charles Albert), 1927- (Box 27)
  - Joseph Shklovsky, Book and Correspondence, 1988-1989; 33.0 items (Box 27)
    This folder contains correspondence between Dr. Friedman and various scientists (including Freeman Dyson) on the publication of a book on Joseph Shklovsky, also known as Iosif Shklovsky.
    Shklovskii, Iosif S.
- Series VII. Committees and Organizations, 10.5 linear feet
  Series VII, the largest in the collection, consists of correspondence, administrative and report material from Dr. Friedman’s membership in various professional and private organizations. The series highlights the prominent role Dr. Friedman played in many organizations, including the American Institute of Aeronautics and Astronautics, the American Philosophical Society, the Cosmos Club, the National Academy of Sciences, the National Aeronautics and Space Administration, as well as the National Research Council. Correspondence in the series is organized as Dr. Friedman’s original files were, by date.
  - 1998 Meeting of the Joint Committee, Minutes, 4.0 items; Joseph Henry Papers Project. (Box 28)
  - 33rd Annual Goddard Memorial Dinner, 1990; 1.0 item; National Space Club. (Box 28)
  - Letters to Dr. Friedman, 1989, 1990; 2.0 items; Academic Press. (Box 28)
    Two letters from Academic Press inviting Dr. Friedman to serve on editorial boards.
  - Eleventh General Assembly, 1961, 1961 July 27-28; 1.0 item; North Atlantic Treaty Organization. Advisory Group for Aeronautical Research and Development. (Box 28)
  - Letters to Herbert Friedman, 1960-1980; 10.0 items; American Academy of Arts and Sciences. (Box 28)
    These letters include Dr. Friedman's acceptance of membership to the American Academy of Arts and Sciences, as well as replies regarding candidates whom Dr. Friedman had nominated for membership.
  - Letters to and from Herbert Friedman, 1961-1978; 107.0 items; American Astronomical Society. (Box 28)
    These letters reflect Dr. Friedman's intense participation and involvement with the American Astronomical Society, over seventeen years.
  - Letters to and from Herbert Friedman, 1958-1973, 1982; 54.0 items; American Geophysical Union. (Box 28)
    These letters reflect Dr. Friedman's great involvement with the American Astronomical Society.
  - Letters to and from Herbert Friedman, 1959-1968; 9.0 items; American Geophysical Union. (Box 28)
    These nine letters reflect Dr. Friedman's involvement with the American Geophysical Union's Monograph Board.
  - Letters to Herbert Friedman, 1968-1969; 4.0 items; American Geophysical Union. (Box 28)
    This folder contains letters to Dr. Friedman, due to his involvement on the American Geophysical Union's Publications Planning Committee.
  - Letters to and from Herbert Friedman, 1994-1995; 5.0 items; American Geophysical Union. (Box 28)
    This folder contains letters reflecting Dr. Friedman's involvement with nominating fellows for the American Geophysical Union's Robert Meier Fellowship.
  - Letters to and from Herbert Friedman, 1982-1983; 4.0 items; American Institute of Aeronautics and Astronautics. (Box 28)
    These letters show Dr. Friedman's editorial involvement with Astronautics and Aeronautics, a publication of the American Institute of Aeronautics and Astronautics.
  - Letters and Article Manuscripts to Herbert Friedman, 1988, 1990; 4.0 items; American Institute of Aeronautics and Astronautics.; Mendillo, M. (Michael); Reynolds, Joseph M. (Box 28)
    These articles were sent to Dr. Friedman, in his editorial capacity of Aerospace America, a publication of the American Institute of Aeronautics and Astronautics.
  - Aerospace America, Article Reprints, 1986-1989; 4.0 items; American Institute of Aeronautics and Astronautics. (Box 28)
    These are article reprints from Aerospace America, to which Dr. Friedman provided editorial oversight. Among these items is an article by Dr. Friedman himself.
  - Aerospace America, Correspondence, 1987-1988, 1989; 16.0 items; American Institute of Aeronautics and Astronautics. (Box 28)
  - Aerospace America, Miscellaneous, 1987, 1989; undated; 3.0 items; American Institute of Aeronautics and Astronautics. (Box 28)
    This folder contains a 14-page editorial strategy for the journal Aerospace America. The date and author are not indicated.
  - Letters to and from Herbert Friedman, 1966-1974; 1987-1988; 1994; 12.0 items; American Institute of Aeronautics and Astronautics. (Box 28)
  - Letters to and from Herbert Friedman, 1979; 11.0 items; American Institute of Aeronautics and Astronautics. (Box 28)
  - Letters to and from Herbert Friedman, 1980-1981; 20.0 items; American Institute of Aeronautics and Astronautics. (Box 28)
  - Global Technology 2000 Conference, Correspondence, 1979-1981; 61.0 items; American Institute of Aeronautics and Astronautics. (Box 28)
  - International Cooperation Award to Herbert Friedman, 1988-1991; 5.0 items; American Institute of Aeronautics and Astronautics. (Box 28)
  - Editorial Advisors Meeting, Minutes, 1967; 2.0 items; American Institute of Aeronautics and Astronautics. (Box 28)
  - Progress in Astronautics and Aeronautics, 1979; 2.0 items; American Institute of Aeronautics and Astronautics. (Box 28)
  - Space Science Review, Correspondence, 1965; 22.0 items; American Institute of Aeronautics and Astronautics. (Box 29)
  - Space Science Review, Correspondence, 1966; 40.0 items; American Institute of Aeronautics and Astronautics. (Box 29)
  - Space Science Review, Correspondence, 1967; 50.0 items; American Institute of Aeronautics and Astronautics. (Box 29)
  - Space Science Review, Correspondence, 1968-1969; 54.0 items; American Institute of Aeronautics and Astronautics. (Box 29)
  - Space Science Review, Correspondence, 1970-1971; 46.0 items; American Institute of Aeronautics and Astronautics. (Box 29)
  - Space Science Review, Correspondence, 1972-1973; 51.0 items; American Institute of Aeronautics and Astronautics.
  - Space Science Review, Correspondence, 1974-1975; 53.0 items; American Institute of Aeronautics and Astronautics. (Box 29)
  - Space Science Review, Correspondence, 1976-1977; 31.0 items; American Institute of Aeronautics and Astronautics.
  - Space Science Review, Correspondence, 1978-1979; 24.0 items; American Institute of Aeronautics and Astronautics. (Box 29)
  - Space Science Review, Correspondence, 1979-1981; 24.0 items; American Institute of Aeronautics and Astronautics. (Box 29)
  - World Space Congress, Correspondence, 1992; 3.0 items; American Institute of Aeronautics and Astronautics. (Box 29)
  - 250th Anniversary Meeting, Minutes, 1993; 6.0 items; American Philosophical Society. (Box 29)
  - Committee for the Magellanic Premium, 1985-1993; 1989-1990; 1992; 27.0 items; American Philosophical Society. (Box 29)
  - Committee on Meetings, 1994; 3.0 items; American Philosophical Society.
    This folder contains the agendas from the American Philosophical Society's Committee on Meetings, for the year 1994.
  - Letters to and from Herbert Friedman, 1964-2000; 34.0 items; American Philosophical Society. (Box 30)
    This folder contains the American Philosophical Society's membership invitation to Herbert Friedman, as well as Dr. Friedman's acceptance. Subsequent letters involve nominations of other scientists for APS membership and organizing many symposia.
  - Letters to and from Herbert Friedman, 1988-2000; 55.0 items; American Philosophical Society. (Box 30)
    This folder contains letters involving the organization of symposia and the nomination of scientists for APS awards.
  - Council Meeting - Agenda, 1994; 1.0 item; American Philosophical Society. (Box 30)
  - Joseph Henry Papers - Correspondence, 1991-1992; 7.0 items; American Philosophical Society. (Box 30)
  - Magellanic Premium, Correspondence, 2000; 12.0 items; American Philosophical Society. (Box 30)
  - Council Meeting Minutes, 1994; 4.0 items; American Philosophical Society. (Box 30)
  - Nominating Committee - Letters to and from Herbert Friedman, 1961-1976; 12.0 items; American Physical Society. (Box 30)
  - Replies to Herbert Friedman, 1995 November 20; 5.0 items; American Physical Society. (Box 30)
    These letters from the American Physical Society respond to Dr. Friedman's nominations of other scientists for the American Physical Society's Fellowship Program.
  - Letters to and from Herbert Friedman, 1959-1962; 23.0 items; American Rocket Society. (Box 30)
    These letters show Dr. Friedman's many activities on several committees of the American Rocket Society.
  - Letters to and from Herbert Friedman, 1966-1980; 13.0 items; Associated Universities, Inc.. (Box 30)
    These letters show Dr. Friedman's involvement on the Board of Trustees of Associated Universities, Inc.
  - Letters and Manuscripts to and from Herbert Friedman, 1974-1979; undated.; 8.0 items; Astrophysical journal. (Box 30)
    These letters and manuscripts show Dr. Friedman's involvement on the Editorial Board of the Astrophysical Journal, which became known as the Astrophysics and Space Science journal.
  - Letters to and from Herbert Friedman, 1967-1981; undated.; 13.0 items; Astrophysical Letters. (Box 30)
  - Letters to and from Herbert Friedman, 1988; 7.0 items; Universitat Bar-Ilan. (Box 30)
  - Letters to and from Herbert Friedman, 1980-1985; 12.0 items; Bellagio Study and Conference Center. (Box 30)
  - Board of Overseers, Correspondence, 1979-1981; 14.0; Harvard College (1780- ). (Box 30)
  - Climate Resources Program, 1987; 1.0 item; Resources for the Future. (Box 30)
  - Letters to and from Herbert Friedman, 1957; 7.0 items; Continental Electric Company. (Box 30)
  - Letters to and from Herbert Friedman, 1968-1990; 19.0 items; Cosmos Club (Washington, D.C.). (Box 30)
  - Nomination Forms for Candidates, 1988; 1992; undated; 3.0 items; Cosmos Club (Washington, D.C.). (Box 30)
  - Letters to and from Herbert Friedman, 1971; 1988-1989; 1998; 16.0 items; COSPAR. (Box 31)
  - Programs from Meetings and Lectures, 1962; 2.0 items; COSPAR. (Box 31)
    This folder contains programs from COSPAR's Fifth Plenary Meeting that took place April 30 to May 9, 1962, and the program for Dr. Friedman's lectures at the Department of State Auditorium, 1962 May 7 1962.
  - Reports and Minutes - Bureau Meetings, 1987-1988; 7.0 items; COSPAR. (Box 31)
    This folder contains reports, agendas, and minutes from the 41st and 42nd Bureau Meeting of COSPAR.
  - Reports and Minutes - Bureau Meeting, 1992; 30.0 items; COSPAR.
    This folder contains reports, agendas, and correspondence about the 48th Bureau Meeting of COSPAR.
  - List of Candidates for COSPAR Positions, 1993 February 2; 2.0 items; COSPAR. (Box 31)
  - Charter and Bylaws, 1992; 2.0 items; COSPAR. (Box 31)
  - Charter, 1984; 1.0 item; COSPAR. (Box 31)
  - Letters to and from Herbert Friedman, 1979-1981; 16.0 items; COSPAR. Scientific Commission E. (Box 31)
  - Eighteenth Annual Plenary Meeting - Conference Correspondence and Materials, 1975; 13.0 items; COSPAR. (Box 31)
  - Nineteenth Annual Plenary Meeting - Correspondence and Materials, 1976; 121.0 items; COSPAR. (Box 31)
  - Conference 1976 - Symposium A, 1975-1976; 56.0 items; COSPAR. (Box 32)
  - Conference 1976 - Symposium E, 59.0 items; COSPAR. (Box 31)
  - Correspondence, 1973; 134.0 items; COSPAR. (Box 32)
    The bulk of this correspondence involves planning and logistics for the COSPAR Conference held in Philadelphia in 1976.
  - Correspondence, 1974; 73.0 items; COSPAR. (Box 32)
    These letters and documents reflect COSPAR's internal affairs and decisions. Dr. Friedman's participation is amply recorded.
  - Correspondence, 1975; 47.0 items; COSPAR. (Box 32)
  - Correspondence, 1988; 1989; 1992; 1993; 17.0 items; COSPAR. (Box 32)
  - Correspondence, 1993; 29.0 items; COSPAR. (Box 32)
  - Draft Rules for the COSPAR Distinguished Service Medal (CDSM), 1993; 1.0 item; COSPAR. (Box 32)
  - Draft Statement of Support for International Space Year, 1986; 2.0 items; COSPAR. (Box 32)
  - Editorial Board - Correspondence, 1977; 5.0 items; COSPAR. (Box 32)
  - Executive Council - Correspondence, 1969-1975; 23.0 items; COSPAR. (Box 32)
  - ICSU Review of COSPAR, 1993; 8.0 items; COSPAR. (Box 32, Box 33)
  - International Solar System Program - A Proposal to COSPAR, undated; 1.0 item; COSPAR. (Box 32, Box 33)
  - International Solar Systems Decade - Proposal and Correspondence, 1974-1975; 24.0 items; COSPAR. (Box 32, Box 33)
  - Meeting, Israel 1977, 1975-1977; 13.0 items; COSPAR. (Box 33)
  - Meeting, Warsaw 1963, 8.0 items; COSPAR. (Box 33)
  - Preliminary Meeting Timetable, COSPAR 1994, 1993; 5.0 items; COSPAR. (Box 33)
  - Rapport sur les comptes de l'exercice, 1992; 1.0 item; COSPAR. (Box 33)
  - Report of the 49th COSPAR Bureau Meeting, 1992; 1.0 item; COSPAR. (Box 33)
  - Rules Concerning Awards and Nominations for Medals, 1993; 3.0 items; COSPAR. (Box 33)
  - Committee on Solar-Terrestrial Research, National Science Foundation/NASA Study Proposal, 1977-1981; 8.0 items; Geophysics Research Forum (U.S.). (Box 33)
  - Ground-Based Solar Terrestrial Physics Study, Correspondence, 1968-1969; 41.0 items; Geophysics Research Forum (U.S.). (Box 33)
  - Visiting Committee, Astronomy, 1975-1979; 18.0 items; Harvard University. Board of Overseers. (Box 33)
  - Correspondence with Science Editor, 1988-1993; 35.0 items; Harvard University. Press. (Box 33)
  - ICARUS: International Journal of the Solar System, Correspondence, 1961-1967; undated; 7.0 items; American Astronomical Society. Division for Planetary Sciences. (Box 34)
  - Correspondence and Reports, 1960-1987; 33.0 items; International Academy of Astronautics. (Box 34)
  - Correspondence, Committee Work, and Reports, 1960-1987; 33.0 items; International Academy of Astronautics. (Box 34)
  - Correspondence, Committee Work, and Reports - Folder 1, 1965-1974; 42.0 items; International Astronomical Union. (Box 34)
  - Correspondence, Committee Work, and Reports, 1958-1981; 1988; 65.0 items; International Astronomical Union. (Box 34)
  - Programs and News Bulletins, 1961; 7.0 items; International Astronomical Union. (Box 34)
    This folder contains paperbound programs and news bulletins relating to the Eleventh General Assembly of the International Astronomical Union held in 1961 at Berkeley, California.
  - Reports on Astronomy, 1971-1973; 20.0 items; International Astronomical Union. Commission 48. (Box 34)
  - The Soft X-Ray Background, Manuscript, 1972; 2.0 items; International Astronomical Union. (Box 34)
  - Friedman Paper Proposals to Symposium -- Correspondence, 1970-1973; 85.0 items; International Astronomical Union. Symposium (55th: 1972: Madrid, Spain). (Box 34)
  - Sixteenth General Assembly - Washington, D.C., 1975-1976; 4.0 items; International Council of Scientific Unions. (Box 34)
  - Friedman's Correspondence and Contribution to Symposium, 1987; 4.0 items; ICSU Symposium on Global Change (1984: Ottawa, Ont.). (Box 34)
  - Correspondence with Dr. Friedman, 1974-1977; 38.0 items; International Council of Scientific Unions. Scientific Committee on Solar-Terrestrial Physics. (Box 34)
  - Report to the SCOSTEP Bureau, 1989; 2.0 items; International Council of Scientific Unions. Scientific Committee on Solar-Terrestrial Physics. (Box 34)
  - Correspondence and Report Prepared for ICSU's Twenty-First General Assembly, Berne, 1986, 1985-1988; 4.0 items; International Geosphere-Biosphere Program "Global Changes". (Box 34)
  - Correspondence with Friedman and Statement, "Cooperation in Space for Peace on Earth", 1987-1988; 12.0 items; International Space Year. (Box 34)
  - Robert Hutchings Goddard Library - Friedman Appointment to International Sponsors Committee, 1966; 5.0 items; Clark University (Worcester, Mass.). Library. (Box 34)
  - Correspondence with Friedman, Organization Plans & Bylaws, 1960-1976; 35.0 items; International Union of Radio Science. (Box 35)
  - Editorial Advisory Board, Correspondence with Friedman, 1967; 4.0 items; Interscience Publishers. (Box 35)
  - Israel Space Agency. Correspondence with Friedman Regarding Experiments Aboard Israeli Satellites., 1988; 5.0 items; Israel. Miśrad ha-mada veha-pituah. Israel. Ministry of Science and Development. (Box 35)
  - Litigation and Correspondence with Herbert Friedman, 1961-1963; 9.0 items; Lionel Electronic Laboratories. (Box 35)
  - Miscellaneous Editorial Positions - Herbert Friedman, 1961-1973; 12.0 items (Box 35)
  - Miscellaneous Invitations, 1960-1977; undated; 29.0 items (Box 35)
  - Miscellaneous Programs, 1949-1991; 19.0 items (Box 35)
  - Five-Year Outlook Report By Herbert Friedman, Folder 1, 1978-1979; 7.0 items; National Academy of Sciences. (U.S.) (Box 35)
  - Five-Year Outlook Report by Herbert Friedman, Folder 2, 1980; 4.0 items; National Academy of Sciences. (U.S.) (Box 35)
  - 109th Space Studies Board Meeting, 1993; 29.0 items; National Academy of Sciences (U.S.). Space Science Board. (Box 35)
  - Correspondence and Work with Ad Hoc Committee on Science and Technology, 1974-1975; 7.0 items; National Academy of Sciences (U.S.). Committee on Science and Technology. (Box 35)
  - Correspondence with Herbert Friedman, 1967-1973; 6.0 items; National Academy of Sciences (U.S.). Advisory Committee on International Organizations and Programs. (Box 35)
  - Annual Audit Committee - Correspondence with Herbert Friedman and Reports, 1993; 4.0 items; National Academy of Sciences. (U.S.) (Box 35)
  - Arthur L. Day Prize - Nominee Thomas F. Malone, 1990; 5.0 items; National Academy of Sciences. (U.S.) (Box 36)
  - Correspondence with Dr. Friedman, Nominations for Inclusion, 1966-1979; 22.0 items; National Academy of Sciences (U.S.). Section of Astronomy. (Box 36)
  - Astronomy Survey Committee. Correspondence with Dr. Friedman., 1969-1971; 14.0 items; National Academy of Sciences. (U.S.) (Box 36)
  - Awards Committee. Correspondence with Dr. Friedman., 1979-1980; 15.0 items; National Academy of Sciences. (U.S.) (Box 36)
  - Board on International Organizations and Programs. Correspondence with Dr. Friedman., 1977-1979; 12.0 items; National Research Council (U.S.). Commission on International Relations. (Box 36)
  - Committee on Scholarly Communication with the People's Republic of China. Correspondence with Dr. Friedman., 1976-1977; 7.0 items; Committee on Scholarly Communication with the People’s Republic of China (U.S.). (Box 36)
  - Letters to and from Dr. Friedman, 1966-1976; 15.0 items; National Academy of Sciences (U.S.). Commitee on Atmospheric Sciences. (Box 36)
  - Correspondence with Dr. Friedman, 1980-1981; 5.0 items; National Academy of Sciences (U.S.). Committee on Human Rights. (Box 36)
  - Correspondence with Dr. Friedman, 1970-1977; 40.0 items; National Research Council (U.S.). Commission on International Relations. (Box 36)
  - Committee on Solar-Terrestrial Research - Correspondence with Dr. Friedman, 1971-1974; 30.0 items; National Research Council (U.S.). Geophysics Research Board. (Box 37)
  - Reports and Correspondence with Dr. Friedman, 1973-1974; 8.0 items; International Magnetospheric Study.; National Academy of Sciences. (U.S.) (Box 37)
  - Letters to and from Herbert Friedman, 1960-1980; 42.0 items; National Academy of Sciences. (U.S.) (Box 37)
  - Letters to and from Herbert Friedman, 1960-1995; 13.0 items (Box 37)
    These letters are directly addressed to Dr. Friedman, as opposed to having been sent as an attachment to Dr. Friedman.
  - Friedman's Election to NAS Council - Correspondence as NAS Councilor, 1979-1982; 40.0 items; National Academy of Sciences. (U.S.)
  - Arthur L. Day Trust Fund - Correspondence of Friedman as Trustee, 1975-1977; 4.0 items; National Academy of Sciences. (U.S.) (Box 37)